Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - American correspondent reports, 1941-1946
    - Norman Page radio report, 1945 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      NORMAN PAGE FROM OKINAWA APR 19th 1945 RATE 3 TIME 13 1/2 MINS
    - Norman Page radio report, 1945 April 21 (Record cabinet)
      Page reports on the destruction of naval ships in the Pacific Theater of World War II. Both American and Japanese losses are recounted.
    - Norman Page radio report on the combined American amphibious forces, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 386: Page interviews various soldiers about their jobs and experiences in war.
    - Norman Page radio reports, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording 377
      Part 2: Recording 378
    - Norman Page radio reports, 1945 April 29 (Record cabinet)
    - Norman Page radio reports, 1945 April 10-11 (Record cabinet)
      Cut 1: Page reports from Okinawa on 10 April 1945
      Cut 2: Page reports on 11 April 1945
    - Norman Page and Bud Foster radio reports, 1945 April 5 (Record cabinet)
      Page and Foster separately report about Okinawa.
    - Norman Page radio report, 1945 April 20 (Record cabinet)
      Page comments on the American effort in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
    - Operation Crossroads Able test radio coverage, 1946 June 30 (Record cabinet)
      Journalists cover the time preceding, including, and following the Able atomic bomb test.
    - Owen Cunningham and Don Bell radio reports, 1946 (Record cabinet)
      Cunningham reports from Honolulu on the tidal waves that struck Hawaii, killing many.
      Bell reports from Tokyo on an election in Japan.
    - Paul Manning radio report, 1945 August 12 (Record cabinet)
      Manning reports from Fleet Headquarters on Pearl Harbor. He speaks about the returning soldiers upon the end of the war with Japan. He also speaks about the conclusion of his reporting on the war, recalling his experiences in Europe and Asia.
    - Paul Manning radio report, 1945 August 19 (Record cabinet)
      Manning describes soldiers praying in honor of the end of war.
    - Paul Manning radio report, 1945 July 6 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 602: Manning reports on the experience of Japanese and American soldiers in the war.
    - Paul Manning radio report from Guam, 1945 August 22 (Record cabinet)
      Manning reports about the last American bomber of Japan, Flight Officer William Shreck, and interviews him. Shreck talks about that mission. Jack Mahon then interviews the soldier that shot down the last Japanese airplane.
    - Paul Manning radio report on the American occupation of Japan, 1945-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Manning reports about the continuing American occupation of Japan. He describes the physical aspects of Japan following the war, as well as the Japanese psyche.
    - Paul Manning radio report, number 201, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Manning reports on the return of an American official after meeting with Japanese officials.
    - Paul Manning radio report, number 205, 1945 August 14 (Record cabinet)
      Manning reports from Guam on the reaction of soldiers to war news.
      The disc label indicates this concerns 10:30:45 until 10:32:00.
    - Paul Manning, Jack Mahon, and Bob Brumby radio reports, 1945 August 26 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Manning and Mahon report on the pending occupation of Japan.
      In the second cut, Brumby reports on the pending occupation of Japan.
      The third cut was intended to be broadcast upon VJ Day.
    - Radio broadcasts concerning the American effort in the Pacific theater of World War II, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, three soldiers describe the Army Service Forces working building a new oil pipeline.
      In the second cut, Don Bell reports prior to the American advancement into Tokyo.
    - Radio broadcasts concerning the Pacific Theater of World War II, 1945 October 8 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 756: Side A is three cuts. First is Paul Monroe reporting on concerns of the United States Navy. The second and third cuts are Don Bell reporting from Tokyo on the politics of Japan. The sound quality indicates the disc was cut from signals received over the airwaves.
      Side B is two cuts. The first cut is Jack Mahon reporting about locations where soldiers and ships come from for the fight in the Pacific. The second cut is Don Bell reporting about Japanese prisoners' release as required by General MacArthur. Bell then reports about wealth the Japanese stole from countries she occupied.
    - Radio interviews concerning the sinking of the Bismarck Sea, 1945 March 30 (Record cabinet)
      Arthur Friend reports from San Francisco and interviews soldiers relating to the sinking of the Bismarck Sea.
    - Radio report about the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 April-May 8 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: A studio report on the United Nations Conference on International Organization.
      Part 2: Jack Mahon interviews American soldiers in the Marianas upon the news of Germany's surrender.
    - Radio report about the battle for Iwo Jima, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      An unidentified journalist describes the importance of Iwo Jima to the American effort in the Pacific, detailing its bombardment and comparing it to D-Day.
    - Radio report, 1945 August 19 (Record cabinet)
      A journalist reports on the return of aircraft in the time of a pending Japanese surrender.
    - Radio report on soldiers' discussions, 1945 April 20 (Record cabinet)
      What do front-line troops talk about on the eve of battle?
    - Radio report on the Japanese surrender in World War II, circa 1945 August 22-23 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, Ed Sauter, Jr. (sp?) reports about the pending Japanese surrender and its effects on China.
      In part 2, Ken McLaughlin speaks about Americans returning to Chungking from Korea whose mission was to check on Allied prisoners-of-war following the Japanese cease-fire.
    - Radio reports about the Yamashita verdict, 1945 December 7 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Undescribed
      Part 2: Robert Stewart reports on the trial and verdict for Yamashita.
      Part 3: An American anchor hosts coverage from Manila about the Yamashita verdict.
    - Radio reports, 1945 August 25 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: In the first cut, Bob Brumby reports from Okinawa before the pending American occupation of Japan about what it was like trying to report on the war for American audiences.
      In the second cut, Brumby records a report to be broadcasted on V-J Day.
      Part 2: In Chungking, Ed Sauter, Jr., interviews soldiers returning to America after being prisoners-of-war.
      From Guam, Paul Manning discusses the delayed American occupation of Japan
    - Radio reports, 1945 August 9 (Record cabinet)
      First cut: Charles Minor reports about China during World War II.
      Other cuts relate to the atomic bombing of Nagasaki.
    - Radio reports, 1945 July 9 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Gordon Walker of the Christian Science Monitor describes the American bombing of Sendai, Japan.
      In the second cut, Cedric Foster reports from Guam on his experiences during the war.
      In the third cut, Gordon Walker reports about aerial fights against Japan.
      The fourth cut is a big picture look by Foster on the importance of the fighting in the Pacific.
      The last cut is a reading of an official communiqué.
    - Radio reports, 1946 March 1-5 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 803: On side A, U.S. Marine Jimmy Jahagen (sp?) talks about the increased cost of living since he's been in the service and how he misses Bethlehem, PA.
      On side B, Don Bell reports from Tokyo on the morale of the soldiers and armed services journalism, especially Stars and Stripes, in Japan.
    - Radio reports from Okinawa, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      This recording is compromised of three cuts.
      The first cut is commercials and the introduction to the Lucky Strikes show starring Jack Benny.
      The second cut is a report transmitted over shortwave from the Pacific. It concerns the fighting in Okinawa.
      The third cut is a report on the advancing American forces on Okinawa.
    - Radio reports, 1945 April 8-May 8 (Record cabinet)
      In part one, R. A. Gunnison interviews Carlos P. Romulo about the implications of VE Day.
      Part two includes a report on armed forces in Europe following V.E. Day and a report from April 1945.
    - Radio reports from World War II, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Ise Marquea (sp?) and Art Pyle report on the arrival of ships.
      Part 2: A studio anchor provides a news update concerning the Pacific Theater during a pending Japanese surrender.
    - Radio reports from the Pacific Theater of World War II, 1945 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Hooley and Tim Lambert report on America's war against Japan. Lambert focuses on being in a foxhole during a conflict.
    - Radio reports on the dropping of the atomic bomb on Nagasaki, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 1650
    - Radio reports, number 645, 1945 August 7 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Don Bell interviews a Sergeant who was wounded several times in the Pacific Theater.
      Part 2: Charles Minor reports from Chungking. He talks about Chinese impressions of the atomic bomb. This is the same program as heard on 58011_a_0011188.
      Part 3: Charles Minor reports about the Chinese reaction to the Soviet entry into the Pacific war. According to the journalists, the Chinese are cautious to pessimistic about this development.
    - Radio reports, number 648, 1945 August 7 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Charles Minor reports from Chungking. He talks about Chinese impressions of the atomic bomb. While mildly patronizing of the Chinese, he notes their approval of the bomb and their hopes for a quick end to the war.
      Part 2: A repeat of part 1.
      Part 3: Paul Manning reports on the implications of the atomic bomb and the Soviet Union joining the Pacific Theater of the war.
      Part 4: Paul Manning reports on the American soldiers' reaction to the Soviet entrance in the Pacific Theater.
      Part 5: Unidentified transmission.
      Part 6: Jack Mahon reports from the third fleet.
      Part 7: Jack Mahon reports from the third fleet on the impact of the atomic bomb and the Soviet entry.
    - Radio transmission of President Roosevelt's and General MacArthur's comments to the Filipino people regarding the fall of Manila, 1945 February 3 (Record cabinet)
      A third voice reads the comments of President Roosevelt and General MacArthur addressed to the Filipino people regarding the fall of Manila.
    - Radio transmissions, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: A report from Admiral Thomas C. Kinkaid of the United States' Seventh Fleet in the Yellow Sea on the fleet's activities.
      Part 2: A recording that seems to be a test recording.
      Part 3: A report on the United States' nuclear policies, especially if the atomic bomb should remain an American secret or turned over to an international body. It then turns to other news items, including a retreat of President Truman and the wedding of Shirley Temple.
      The sound recording is poor due to deformations of the source disc.
    - Radio transmissions, 1945 August 8-9 (Record cabinet)
      The transmissions concern the fighting in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
    - Radio transmissions from the World War II era., 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      On side A of this disc recording, Tim Lemmett reports for the combined networks on the bombing of Tokyo.
      The recording on Side B includes several programs talking over each other, but the majority is an audition recording that includes news updates on World War II as well as commercials.
    - Red Cross radio report recording number 246, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      An American journalist interviews American citizens that have been in the Pacific Theater of WWII before they depart to return home. The sound quality features significant jamming and is almost completely unintelligible.
      Copy 2 is the longest.
    - Robert Stewart radio report, 1946 April 23 (Record cabinet)
      Stewart talks about the election in Manila.
    - Robert Stewart radio report number 779, 1945 December 1 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Incidental sounds from transmission.
      Part 2: Stewart reports from Manilla on the men needed for occupation forces. He says this will come from volunteer reenlistment. He notes a volunteer army is the best one can get. He interviews a sergeant who is reenlisting. The sergeant says he went from thinking one would be crazy to reenlist to thinking it was crazy to not reenlist, citing the generous benefits and the ability of his family to move to where he will be stationed. The sergeant believes he will stay in the army until retirement.
      Part 3: A studio roundup of war news.
    - Robert Stewart radio reports, 1945 December 2-5 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, Stewart reports from Manila about reenlistment of soldiers in the military. The soldier he interviews explains how the army pays better than the private sector.
      Also in part 1 are two administrative conversations.
      In part 2, Stewart speaks about his interview with General Yamashita, who was awaiting trial at the time.
      Also in part 2 is a recording of the 97th infantry division chorus performing Christmas carols.
    - Robert Stewart, Cedric Foster, and Don Bell radio reports, 1945 December 18 (Record cabinet)
      Stewart reports from Manila on the crime rate in the Philippines and the not guilty plea of a Japanese general.
      Foster reports from Boston on British and French matters.
      Bell reports from Tokyo on the war crimes trials of Japanese military figures.
    - Robert Stuart radio reports from 31 October and part of a Sherlock Holmes radio drama from 17 September, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 771: Stuart reports on the trial of an accused Japanese war criminal and other acts of brutality by Japanese soldiers.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio report and John Thorton audio letter to Mrs. Thompson, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Gunnison reports about the American advances in the Philippines. He concentrates on Ormoc.
      Part 2: John Thorton of the Mutual Broadcasting System news division in San Francisco makes a recording intended for Mrs. Thompson, whose son, Chick, is stationed in the Pacific and was interviewed for the radio. He includes instructions on how to properly play the disc.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio report, 1944 December 11 (Record cabinet)
      Gunnison provides an update on the war. He discusses Ormoc before analyzing the Japanese soldier.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio report, 1944 November 22 (Record cabinet)
      Gunnison reports from the Philippines on Thanksgiving Day. He covers the morale of the soldiers on the holiday.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio report, 1944 December 4 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Gunnison reports on the Filipino backlash against Japanese bombing.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio report on US soldiers at Christmas, circa 1944 December 24-25 (Record cabinet)
      Gunnison reports from the Philippines on the experience of the U.S. soldiers in the Pacific at Christmas.
      Part 2 of copy 2 is poor due to the cut on the original disc being crossed out with wax. Part 3 of copy 2 includes dramatized instructions for women writing their GI beaus.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio reports, 1944 November 1 and 17 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 1 November 1944, Gunnison, based in the Philippines, provides an update on the Pacific Theater.
      Part 2: Gunnison reports on what the Filipinos are doing with those that had contact with the Japanese occupation forces.
    - Royal Arch Gunnison radio reports, 194? November 17 and 22 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Gunnison reports on November 17 on the trial of Filipino natives that collaborated with the Japanese forces.
      Part 2: Gunnison reports from the Philippines on Japanese radio propaganda.
    - Sound recording of General Douglas MacArthur and Don Bell radio reports from Bikini Lagoon, 1946 July 4-25 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: General MacArthur talks about the return of independence to the Philippines.
      Part 2: Bell reports 24 hours after the Baker atomic bomb test at Bikini Lagoon. He is "inside the lagoon, safe, and within four miles of the target array." He then explains the safety period following an atomic explosion and when radioactivity becomes dangerous. He describes the lagoon as "a lagoon of death," relaying the results of the test from Admiral Blandy.
      Part 3: Bell reports on the USS Saratoga following the Baker atomic bomb test. He notes this is a turning point for the Navy, and yet the reasons for the ship collapsing are unknown.
      Part 4: Bell reports how accidental discovery during the Able atomic bomb test of using polarized lenses to trace atomic clouds aided the research conducted during the Baker test.
      Part 5: Bell reports after the Baker atomic bomb test on the continuing effects of nuclear weapons on the future of Naval ships.
    - Sound recordings, 1945 May 5-6 (Record cabinet)
      The first cut on this disc is corrections to the script for the program Meet Your Navy, 5 May 1945.
      In the second cut, Joe Heinlein reports on 6 May 1945.
      The third cut is nothing but noise. The label on the disc says the program was "washed out."
    - Sound recordings of comments of naval leaders on atomic explosions, 1946 July (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: A reporter interviews Secretary of the Navy Forrestal the day after the Able test of Operation Crossroads. Forrestal had just returned from inspecting the target fleet, and he answers questions from radio correspondents aboard the USS Mt. McKinley. The Secretary notes it is too early to draw conclusions from the test. He was most surprised by the inspection that heavy ships did not receive that much damage.
      Part 2: Vice Admiral Blandy offers his statement on the results of the first underwater atomic bomb explosion.
    - Special Army Day 1945 radio broadcast, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
      A produced Mutual Broadcasting System radio program, several U.S. military leaders report on the war effort in the Pacific Theater.
      The speakers: Lt. Gen. Richardson, Maj. Gen. Chaney, Lt. Gen. Buckner, Vice Adm. Turner, and Adm. Nimitz.
    - Special Christmas program with Don Bell, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Bell hosts a Christmas program from Tokyo. It features readings from the Bible and carols performed by the 97th Infantry Division Chorus.
    - Sport show, 1946 May 24 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1 sounds like a play in Japanese.
      Part 2, also in Japanese, sounds much more like a program about sports.
      The only label on the disc is on the second side, which reads: SPORT SHOW FRIDAY 24 MAY 1946
    - Sun Fo radio address, 1945 April 12 (Record cabinet)
      Bob Brumby presents Dr. Sun Fo. The Chinese dignitary speaks about what his country hopes to accomplish at the United Nations Conference on International Organization in San Francisco.
    - Susan Tate and Gordon Walker radio reports, 1945 July 13 (Record cabinet)
      Tate reports from Manila for the American Red Cross. She interviews a Filipino actress whose life was radically changed by the Japanese. She then interviews Paul Thompson, another Red Cross worker, about the Manila Club.
      Walker, a reporter for the Christian Science Monitor, reports from Guam about the American fighting against the Japanese.
    - Susan Tate radio report from Manila, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Tate reports for the American Red Cross on how the United States fits within the United Nations. She interviews American and Australian soldiers.
    - Susan Tate radio report, number 747, 1945 September 29 (Record cabinet)
    - Susan Tate, Bob McCloud, and Fred Baxter radio reports, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, Tate interviews people.
      In part 2, McCloud and Baxter separately report about Korea.
    - Tim Leimert radio report, number 480, 1945 April 26 (Record cabinet)
      Leimert reports from off the coast of Okinawa about the action against Japanese forces in the area.
    - Tim Leimert radio report, number 447, 1945 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      Leimert reports from Okinawa about his experiences with the soldiers in battle. He interviews Leo Ford of the 96th division; Ford recounts his experience in the battle of Okinawa.
    - Tim Leimert and Don Bell radio reports, 1945 June 11-2 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 562
      Side A, 11 June 1945: Leimert reports about American actions at Okinawa; Don Bell reports about American advances on Borneo.
      Side B, 12 June 1945: Bell interviews Bob Brumby about the similarities and differences between China and the Philippines; Leimert reports about the Japanese forces and an American offer to start surrender talks.
    - Tim Leimert and R. A. Gunnison radio reports, 1944 November 13 (Record cabinet)
      Leimert reports on battles for Guam in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
      Administrative transmissions from 12 November 1944 are also on the original disc.
      R. A. Gunnison reports from the Philippines on Stalin labeling Japan an aggressor nation.
    - Tim Leimert and Gene Rider radio reports, 194? November 24 (Record cabinet)
      Leimert and Rider report about the American invasion of Japan.
      The label on side A of the source disc reads: Nov 24, Tokyo Raid, Fed to Brown
      The label on side B of the source disc reads: Tim Lemmert #70 interviews Gen Hansell and Sgt Marvin, Guam Pool, Nov 24, 2+3
    - Tim Leimert radio report, 194? November 24 (Record cabinet)
      Leimert reports from Saipan on the beginning of aerial bombardment of Japan.
    - Unintelligible program and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 August 28 (Record cabinet)
      707A
      707
      Gen Wainwright
      Show absolutely no good
      Noise level too high
      Jack Mahon
      Aug 28 45
      Okinawa B
      "C" Sgt Gross Iwo Jima 8/28/45 Rate 3 Time 2'05"
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1946 March 6 (Record cabinet)
      Robb introduces Sergeant Bulatao to describe Hidden Valley. He focuses on both the physical layout and the culture.
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1946 February 28 (Record cabinet)
      Robb describes a reunion of people that spent time in internment camps.
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1946 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      Robb interviews 12-year-old Antonio "Tony" Marcus Bautista. Bautista's father frequently aided anti-Japanese rebels in the Philippines and was twice jailed for these efforts. Robb and Tony discuss the elder Bautista.
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1945 September 3 (Record cabinet)
      File No. P-1353-E
      Robb honors the Americans and Filipinos interred at Camp O'Donnell.
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1945 September 21 (Record cabinet)
      Walter Robb interviews Army Major Silva. Robb introduces Silva, talks about Silva's family and career, and mentions that Silva was injured but is currently undergoing treatment.
      During the interview proper, Silva covers a lot of ground. He goes over battle stories and wounds he's sustained, describes the communications of the armed forces, describes the opposing forces, and talks about his family, who are currently in Australia.
    - Walter Robb broadcast recording, 1945 October 17 (Record cabinet)
      Robb reflects on the death of his son in service and how this compares to other Americans' experience and the war effort.
    - Waverly Edwards radio report, 1945 April (Record cabinet)